# **Rishab Jain**

408.508.8064 rishabxjain@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/rishab-jain- GitHub: github.com/RishabJain27 Portfolio: rishabjain27.github.io

#### >SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with 3+ years of experience with demonstrated success in developing and maintaining software systems to increase reliability and performance. Seeking to leverage former experience and problem solving abilities to build exceptional software in my next role.

#### >PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Stealth Startup | Founding Engineer, Part Time | Cupertino, CA

Jan 2024 - Present

- Pre-seed startup targeting the musical composition industry.
- Building a web application based on ReactJS for user-interface along with Python/Flask for full-stack development.

## Cisco | Software Engineer | San Jose, CA

July 2020 - Sep 2023

- Collaborated with a cross-functional team of six to develop new features for Plug-And-Play service in Cisco DNAC which helps manage device configurations for various network devices for Enterprise platforms.
- Implemented Java RESTful web services using Spring Framework to manage device workflows and settings.
- Developed features in Plug-And-Play service to improve user experience using Javascript/ReactJs, resulting in a 20% reduction time for networking devices to be configured.
- Optimized existing Plug-And-Play service to improve performance and scalability by refactoring codebase and improving database queries to MongoDB leading to an increase in device-handling capacity by 50%.
- Identified and resolved issues reported by clients and QA resulting in enhanced reliability and improved overall stability of Plug-And-Play service.
- Conducted live debugging sessions with customers to promptly identify and resolve issues, ensuring a seamless customer experience.
- Automated hundreds of manual tests using Selenium and Python bolstering the efficiency of bug detection in the codebase and improving software reliability by 15%.
- Collaborated with engineers, product managers, and UI/UX designers on all aspects of the software development cycle including design, planning, development, and testing.
- Managed Docker orchestration and containerization using Kubernetes.

# Automation Anywhere | Software Engineer, Intern | San Jose, CA

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

- Developed Windows Installation GUI applications to reduce installation time of software bots across the Process Discovery product using C++ and MFC as a member of the Installer team consisting of two other engineers, designed to check computer specifications (RAM, memory, OS) during software installation.
- Led development of an auto-restarter program utilizing C++ to restart the application as part of the final installation process, reducing installation time by 25%.

#### Session AI | Software Engineer, Intern | Milpitas, CA

July 2018 - Sep 2018

- Led implementation of recommendation carousel for restaurants based on user's location for major resort chain's websites improving customer experience for thousands of customers using Python and Apache Solr.
- Incorporated Instagram API into JavaScript and Node.js backend to display client's Instagram content on site.

## >EDUCATION

#### **B.S. Computer Science,** *University of California, Santa Cruz*

Jun 2020

• Relevant Coursework: Abstract Data Types and Algorithms, Algorithm Analysis, Computer System Designs, Networking, Computer Architecture, Computer Graphics, Mobile Apps, Databases, Computer Security, Al

## >PROJECT WORK

# **Algorithmic Trading | Github**

Oct 2023

Algorithm to generate investment trading advice on companies in the S&P 500 using various trading strategies
Newly Released Sneakers | <u>Github</u> | <u>live URL</u>
Apr 2020 - Jun 2020

• Web Application displaying newly released sneakers from Nike, Adidas, and Under Armour

#### >LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

Java, JavaScript, Python, C++, React, Spring, SQL, MongoDB, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Git